A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Vice President, Office Files of Mary E. McClymont FA594
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1981-2008; II
  - Police -- Assessment Resource Center -- Notes and Correspondence Re: Grant, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Police -- Descriptions of Current FF Programming, Feb 1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Police -- Funds from PSJ/OVP Budget -- Memoranda, Nov 2, 2000-Jan 10, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Program Learning Groups -- Update Memos, Feb 20, 1997-Dec 21, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Right to Health (UN Conference) -- Meeting Book, Apr 30, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rights and Social Justice Program Meeting, Cape Town, South Africa -- Meeting Book, May 23-25, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Robinson, Mary -- Memorandum with Comments on Ethical Globalization Initiative, Jan 11-Feb 15, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Sexuality and Reproductive Health Meeting, Johannesburg, South Africa -- Meeting Book, Mar 26-28, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - South Africa -- Follow Up on Discussions of Memo on South Africa and Government/NGO Cooperation, Oct 21, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - South and Southeast Asia -- Hand-Over Memo for the Rights and Social Justice Program in India, Sri Lanka and Nepal, Apr 30, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Southern Africa -- Grant Evaluation Reports, 1984-1997 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Southern Education Foundation -- Proposal, Correspondence Re: Grant, 2006-2007 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Articles, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Transition -- PSJ Senior Director Post -- Memoranda with Attachments, Nov 20, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - United Nations -- Notes and Background on Fund for International Partnership, FF UN-Related Programming, Jun 28, 1995-Feb 29, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - United Nations -- UN High Commissioner for Refugees -- Dennis McNamara Testimony, Information on Refugees, Oct 8, 1998-Aug 2, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - United Nations and World Bank Meetings -- Notes, Sep-Oct 2000 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Social Forum -- Correspondence Re: IIE, Notes, Grant Information, Background, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Vector Project -- Memoranda, Meeting Notes, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Vector Project -- Papers -- Project Work Binder, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Vector Project -- Working File -- Correspondence, Memoranda, 1998-2000 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Vera Institute -- Grant Recommendations, Correspondence, Background, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Vera Institute -- International Police Accountability Project -- Proposal, Memoranda Re: Project Meetings, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Vera Institute -- Working File -- Notes, Correspondence Re: Grants, 1997-2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Vera Institute -- Workshop on Police in Democratic Society, Harriman, NY -- Meeting Book (1 of 2), Mar 23-25, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Vera Institute -- Workshop on Police in Democratic Society, Harriman, NY -- Meeting Book (2 of 2), Mar 23-25, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - West Africa -- Office Visit -- Briefing Book, Feb 12-19, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Women, HIV/AIDs and the Global Fund Meeting -- Agenda, Notes, Background, Jan 28-29, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Women's Fund Social Justice Collaborative Meeting -- Meeting Book, Correspondence, Nov 5, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Women's Rights Litigation Fund -- Status Report, Dec 22, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - World Bank -- Seminar on Civil Society, Foreign Aid and Sustainable Development -- Notes, Background, Jun 21, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Worldwide Governance Meeting -- Learning -- Minutes, Oct 18-21, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Worldwide International Cooperation Field Meeting, Santa Monica, CA -- Meeting Book (1 of 2), Mar 27-29, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Worldwide International Cooperation Field Meeting, Santa Monica, CA -- Meeting Book, Notes (2 of 2), Mar 27-29, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Worldwide Philanthropy Group Meeting, Tarrytown, NY -- Meeting Book, Jan 5-7, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Reports, 1969-2008; III
  This series contains reports by consultants and Ford program staff. A number of the reports were created before Ms. McClymont joined the Foundation in 1988. Topics include legal reform and human rights work in Latin America. A few reports pertain to democratization and human rights in Chile. Other reports discuss legal reform in Vietnam, citizenship in Brazil, and university law clinics in South America. This series also holds several reports on trips to Sri Lanka, Latin America, and Russia, the Czech Republic and Poland.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - "The International Legal Studies Program of the Ford Foundation" by Murray L. Schwartz, Dec 1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Legal Education" by Arthur von Mehren, Jan 17, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Public Interest Law and Human Rights in Brazil" by David Trubek, May 30, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "Law and Social Justice: Brazil" by David Trubek, Dec 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "Work with the South African Legal Resources Centre" by George Cooper, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Survey of the Current Status of National Women's Rights Organizations" by Marjorie Fine Knowles, Oct 26, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Expanding Justice: Review of the Ford Foundation Legal Services Program" by Dorothy J. Samuels, Jan 1984 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Status Report on Foundation Work in Dispute Resolution", Dec 1985 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - "Encouraging Stability, Peace and Justice in the International Order" by Joseph S. Nye, Jr., I.M. Destler, I.G. Patel and Jose Zalaquett, Jun 1987 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "Pluralism and Diversity" by Nathan I. Huggins, Mary Schmidt Campbell, Elaine R. Jones and Jose Zalaquett, Jun 1987 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "Evaluation of the Chilean Commission for Human Rights and the Vicarate of Solidarity" by Margaret E. Crahan, Oct 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Legal Reform in the USSR and Possibilities for Western Help" by Valery Chalidze, Mar 1, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Report to the Ford Foundation on Legal Services Support Centers" by Leah Wortham and Robert Dinerstein, Nov 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Making Rights Real: Human Rights in Latin America and the Caribbean" by Scott Busby, Dec 1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Sugerencias Para el Trabajo de Organizaciones no Gubernamentales de Derechos Humanos en Peru y Argentina" by Lucenciada Patricia Tappata de Valdez, Dec 31, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Human Rights in South America" by Juan E. Mendez, Jan 1, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Sri Lanka Trip Report" by R. Sudarshan, Feb 20, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - "Chile: Human Rights in Transition" by Cynthia Brown, Sep 1, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - "Towards Justice: Foundation Programs in Human Rights and Social Justice and Governance and Public Policy in the Philippines" by Terrence George, Feb 20, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - "Problems of Citizenship in Brazil" by James Holston, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - "Trip to Latin America" (Colombia, Peru and Chile) by Mary McClymont, Jan 9, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "The Ford Foundation and International Security" by Catherine McArdle Kelleher and Robert O'Neill, Apr 1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - "Legal Education and Research and Law Reform in Vietnam" by Mark Sidel, Apr 1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - "The Challenge for the Decade of the '90s: A Survey of Trends and Issues Related to Refugees, Asylees, Migrants and the Internally Displaced" by Guy Goodwin-Gill, Gil Loescher and Julia Taft, May 1992 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - "Ford Foundation Rights and Social Justice Program Meeting, Cape Town, South Africa" (rapporteur notes), May 23-27, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - "Report on the Status of University Law Clinics in South Africa" by M. Shanara Gilbert, Nov 15, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "Promoting Rights and Social Justice: A Historical Survey of Ford Foundation Programs for African American and Latino Communities" by Sarita Ahuja, Nov 1994 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - "Trip to Russia, Czech Republic and Poland" by Mary McClymont, Nov 22, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - "The Ford Foundation's International Human Rights Program: A History and an Agenda" by Margo Picken, Jan 30, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - "Municipal Government and Political Participation in Chile" by Gary Bland, Feb 28, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - "Fiscalización y Control Ciudadanos en un Régimen Político Democrático: Los Casos de Colombia, Chile, Argentina y Perú" by Hugo Frühling, [1996] (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - "Una Vez Más la Miseria: Es Chile un País Sustenable?" by Marcel Claude, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - "Políticas Ambientales en Chile, 1990-1995" by Laura Mullahy, Mar 1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - "From Political Liberalization to Democratization" by Jonathan N. Moyo, Apr 30, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Beyond Boundaries (Toronto: University of Toronto, 1997) by Navnita Chadha Behera, Paul M. Evans and Gowher Rizvi (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "History of the Ford Foundation's Work on Police Issues" by Michelle Dash, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "Reporte para la Fundación Ford" (Legal Clinics and Public Interest Law Report) by Martin Federico Bohmer, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Round Table on Law and Justice in Brazil" by David Trubek, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "A Measure of Choice: A Strategic Review of the Madaripur Legal Aid Association's Current Impact and Possible Future Directions" by Stephen Golub, Jan 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "Adapting the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative to Latin America" by Ramón Borges Méndez, Apr 4, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "Review of the Ford Foundation Human Rights and Social Justice Program in the Middle East and North Africa" by Emma Playfair, May 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "Decentralization, Local Governance and Democracy in Chile", Jun 16, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Public Interest Actions in the Andean Region and Southern Cone Region", Jun 25, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Symposium on Public Interest Law in Eastern Europe and Russia" (report) by Public Interest Law Initiative, Jun 29-Jul 8, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "The Environment, Sustainable Development and Democratization in Chile", Jul 14, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Nongovernmental Organizations in Chile", Jul 23, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "Assessment of Public Interest Law Initiative (PILI) in Bangladesh" by Stephen Golub, Sep 22, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - "A Review of the Ford Foundation's Work Related to Hispanics in the U.S." by Evelyn Dávila, José Roberto Juárez, Jr. and Edwin Meléndez, Nov 1997 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - "Juridical Services as a Strategy for Combating Racism" by Dora Luca de Lima Bertulio, Feb 1998 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "Reflections on Encounter Groups of Jews and Palestinians from Israel" by Haggith Gor Ziv and Rela Mazali, Apr 1998 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - "The Innovations in Government Programs" by Judith Tendler, Apr 14, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - "Gay and Lesbian Concerns: Past, Current and Future Programming by the Ford Foundation" by Priscilla Hayner, Jul 29, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - "Evaluation of Institutions of Higher Learning Supported by the Ford Foundation in East-Central Europe in the 1990s and Recommendations for the Future" by Daniel Chirol and Miroslawa Grabowska, Aug 16, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - "Building the Latin American Human Rights Field" by Dr. Joan Dassin, Sep 24, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - "Ford Foundation Peace and Social Justice Program Worldwide Meeting, Krakow, Poland, Jun 4-9, 2000: Rapporteur's Report", Jul 5, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - "A Review of UN Reform-Related Projects Supported by the Ford Foundation, 1985-1996" by Edward C. Luck, May 25, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - "Towards Enhanced Work on Conflict" by Teresa Whitfield, Jul 2, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - "Deepening Democracy Worldwide" by Christopher Reardon, Jan 7, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 24)